What's up?
In this clip I will be discussing the importance of understanding how to live in a dorm, a pod or a room setting in the prison system.
A lot of people have a misconcept about it, they think that people are sitting on cots behind bars and quiet usually that's not the case.
The county jail basically houses people in the forms of pods where they have several different rooms inside of the pods and you're living in a space that's extremely small without any storage.
Once you get to the state institution level or the prerelease central level, you may find yourself in a dorm style setting with a rows upon rows with steal bunk beds and the only space that is actually yours is that that exist between the two of your bed and the bed next to you and a lock box that slides underneath the bottom bunk.
That lock box is usually about 2 1/2 x 1 1/2 feet and it's about a foot deep.
So you've got to figure out a way to confine your living and all of the things that you own or possess in a very small environment.
Once you get to the prerealese level, you may be fortunate enough to stay in a room with maybe only 4 or 3 other people, a 4 man room total.
Under those circumstances you begin to realize that there are certain things you have to do in order to be comfortable and healthy as well.
Cleanliness is next to God in the prison system because you don't have a lot space and because there is a lot of confinement you can find yourself subject to different infections and diseases, illnesses that you may not necessarily come across so readily if you were out walking around in the streets everyday.
But they do provide you with a lot of cleaning supplies.
You can keep your environment very clean, it helps you, it helps your roommate, it helps the people around you and keeps the peace to a very great level.
It's a small space that you're living in, you've got to figure out different ways to do it, different ways to manipulate it so that you're not in violation of the rules of the institution or in violation of other people's space and it's not an easy thing to do.